<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intro to Git and Github on</title><link>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/</link><description>Recent content in Intro to Git and Github on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 19:13:18 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Is Git?</title><link>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/what-is-git/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 19:13:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/what-is-git/</guid><description>So, what exactly is git?
Git is a version control system (VCS). A version control system is similar to taking backups of your code. So, at any time, you can go and find previous version of your code. This is really helpful when you have accidentally introduced a bug in your code and want to go back to the previous version where there were no bugs.
Another major thing to note is that git is also a distributed version control system.</description></item><item><title>Terminal Basics</title><link>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/terminal-basics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 19:45:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/terminal-basics/</guid><description>When using git from the command line, it can be really helpful to know about some commands to help you with basic navigation. So, let us quickly go through a few of them.
cd - Change Directory ls - List Directory Contents mkdir - Make Directory pwd - Print Working Directory Other useful commands:
code . - Open current folder in Visual Studio Code explorer . - Open current folder in file explorer on Windows open .</description></item><item><title>Creating a Repository</title><link>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/creating-a-repository/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 23:20:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/creating-a-repository/</guid><description>To demonstrate the use of git and github, let us create a simple website.
Navigate to project folder # First, open up the terminal and navigate to the folder where we want to create the website.
You can go to a particular folder using the cd (Change Directory) command. For example:
cd C:\Users\Username\Documents Then create the folder for the website itself using the mkdir (Make Directory) command like so:</description></item><item><title>What Is Github?</title><link>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/what-is-github/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 14:48:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/what-is-github/</guid><description>GitHub is a cloud hosting platform that allows you to host your git repositories online allowing you to collaborate with others.
GitHub also allows you to host static website using GitHub Pages.
Creating a github account # Go to github.com and create an account by hitting sign up to get started.
Installing GitHub Desktop # Go to desktop.github.com to download and install GitHub Desktop which is a desktop application which allows to manage git repositories.</description></item><item><title>Publishing to Github</title><link>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/publishing-to-github/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 15:04:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/publishing-to-github/</guid><description>We are going to use GitHub desktop to upload our repository to github.
To get started, open the github desktop application.
To open the repository in github desktop select the Add an Existing Repository from your hard drive... option. Then select the folder containing your website.
Now publish the repository to github by selecting the publish repository option.
Now go to github.com or click the View on GitHub button to see the published repository on your github account.</description></item><item><title>Deploying to Github Pages</title><link>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/deploying-to-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 16:02:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/deploying-to-github-pages/</guid><description>We can now publish our website by first going to the repository on github and clicking on the pages tab under the settings.
Then under source, select the main branch as the source and hit save.
Then wait for a few minutes and the site will be published with the link provided to you.
If you open up the website link provided to you in the pages tab under settings.</description></item><item><title>Cloning a Repository</title><link>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/cloning-a-repository/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 15:04:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://code-explorer.github.io/events/docs/intro-to-git-and-github/cloning-a-repository/</guid><description>Let us loot at how you can edit a repository already on github.
First, to edit any repository you need to be its owner. If these is an open source repository on github that you want to edit. You can use the clone option to make the copy of that repository with you as its owner. Let us try doing this with a repository.
Head to this sample repository on github: Sample Repository - Sudoku</description></item></channel></rss>